Finding Aid for Carroll DeWeese digital map collection, 1838-1926.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Carroll DeWeese digital map collection 1838-1926
DeWeese, Carroll
56 maps and other images on 1 DVD-R
2010136 Aa 2
Maps of Oakland and Livingston Counties and Detroit, Mich., and the state of Michigan, and other items relating to Bloomfield Township, Mich., photographed from the holdings of the Burton Historical Collection, Detroit Public Library.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Carroll DeWeese (donor 10363 ), in 2010.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Carroll DeWeese is a Birmingham, Mich., photographer.
This collection of maps and other items was photographed from the holdings of the Burton Historical Collection, Detroit Public Library, May 5, 2010. Five items or groups of items were photographed.
Subjects:
Detroit (Mich.)--Maps.; DeWeese, Carroll.; Livingston County (Mich.)--Maps.; Michigan--Maps.; Resder, Jerome & Duffield's Subdivision (Detroit, Mich.)--Maps.
Contributors:
Cram, George Franklin, 1841-1928. Michigan. 1882.; Hess, F. Map of Oakland County, Michigan.; Hubbard, Bela, 1814-1896. Michigan maps. Vol.8, Oakland and Livingston Counties.
- Burton Historical Collection maps on DVD-R
  - 1857 Oakland Map (Box 7)
    Map of Oakland County, Michigan, 1857. Published by S.H. Burhans; Surveyor F. Hess; Large Wall Map (5 feet wide by 6 feet tall) stored in the archives as three 2'x6' strips. Burton Historical Collection call number 977.402 [1857] H46
    - 1857 Oakland Map All.jpg [entire county]
    - 1857 Oakland Map Bottom.jpg [southern tier of townships, Pontiac, and vignettes]
    - 1857 Oakland Map Middle.jpg [townships 2-4 north, town plats, and vignettes]
    - 1857 Oakland Map Top.jpg [part of townships 4 north, townships 5 north, town plats, and vignettes]
  - 1879 Plat Maps
    Plat of Reader, Jerome & Duffield's Subdivision, 1879. Street and lot plat in two (2) pages. One page is somewhat stained on the top portion. The second page is in excellent condition. This subdivision is in the Springwells area of southwest Detroit. Burton Historical Collection call number 977.4D4 1879 M92 (Rare Map)
    - 1879 Plat Map A.jpg
    - 1879 Plat Map B.jpg
  - 1882 Michigan Map
    Michigan, 1882. Geo. F. Cram, Engraver & Publisher; copyright secured 1882; Single page color map of Michigan -- both Lower and Upper Peninsulas (approx. 15"x18")
    - 1882 Michigan Map.jpg
  - 1911 Auction Notice
    Auction Sale -- Monday, Aug. 28th 1911, Hupp Stock Farms, On Maple Ave. -- one mile west of Birmingham. This is a notice of an estate sale for the Hupp Farm which was soon to be developed into the Bloomfield Village Subdivisions by Judson Bradway. 95 separate items to be auctioned are listed. Burton Historical Collection call number 099.7745 B53 D4
    - 1911 Auction Notice.jpg
  - 1926 Covert Article
    "The Covert," Article from The Afterglow, Vol. 2, Issue 8-9, Aug/Sep 1926, pages 5, 6, 7, and 27. The "Covert" was the name given by the Hendrie sisters to what is now known as the Barton House in Bloomfield Township. The Afterglow was monthly Magazine about life in the Birmingham Bloomfield area published for the years 1925--1927.
    - Covert A.jpg
    - Covert B.jpg
    - Covert C.jpg
    - Covert D.jpg
  - Hubbard Maps
    Michigan Maps -- Bela Hubbard, 1838-1841, Vol. 8, Oakland and Livingston Counties. Each township in the two counties is drawn on a separate sheet (approx 12"x12") and loosely bound in book. These are the original maps drawn by Surveyor Bela Hubbard, and show land forms and vegetation. Burton Historical Collection call number 977.4 [1838-1841] H86 V.8
    - Hubbard01.jpg [Oakland County introduction]
    - Hubbard02.jpg [Royal Oak Townshp]
    - Hubbard03.jpg [Troy Township]
    - Hubbard04.jpg [Avon Township]
    - Hubbard05.jpg [Oakland Township]
    - Hubbard06.jpg [Addison Township]
    - Hubbard07.jpg [Southfield Township]
    - Hubbard08.jpg [Bloomfield Township]
    - Hubbard09.jpg [Pontiac Township]
    - Hubbard10.jpg [Orion Township]
    - Hubbard11.jpg [Oxford Township]
    - Hubbard12.jpg [descriptive text]
    - Hubbard13.jpg [Farmington Township]
    - Hubbard14.jpg [West Bloomfield Township]
    - Hubbard15.jpg [Waterford Township]
    - Hubbard16.jpg [Independence Township]
    - Hubbard17.jpg [Brandon Township]
    - Hubbard18.jpg [Novi Township]
    - Hubbard19.jpg [Commerce Township]
    - Hubbard20.jpg [White Lake Township]
    - Hubbard21.jpg [Springfield Township]
    - Hubbard22.jpg [Groveland Township]
    - Hubbard23.jpg [Lyon Township]
    - Hubbard24.jpg [Milford Township]
    - Hubbard25.jpg [Highland Township]
    - Hubbard26.jpg [Rose Township]
    - Hubbard27.jpg [Holly Township]
    - Hubbard28.jpg [Livingston County introduction]
    - Hubbard29.jpg [Green Oak Township]
    - Hubbard30.jpg [Brighton Township]
    - Hubbard31.jpg [Hartland Township]
    - Hubbard32.jpg [Tyrone Township]
    - Hubbard33.jpg [Hamburg Township]
    - Hubbard34.jpg [Genoa Township]
    - Hubbard35.jpg [Osceola Township, now Oceola Township]
    - Hubbard36.jpg [Deerfield Township]
    - Hubbard37.jpg [Putnam Township]
    - Hubbard38.jpg [Marion Township]
    - Hubbard39.jpg [Howell Township]
    - Hubbard40.jpg [Tuscola Township, now Cohoctah Township]
    - Hubbard41.jpg [Unadilla Township]
    - Hubbard42.jpg [Iosco Township]
    - Hubbard43.jpg [Handy Township]
    - Hubbard44.jpg [Iona Township, now Conway Township]